On September 3, 1973
a blue fly capable of flapping
70 beats a minute
landed on St. Vincent Street
in Montmartre.
At that moment, on
a restaurant terrace nearby
the wind magically made
two glasses dance unseen
on a tablecloth.
Meanwhile, in a 5th-floor flat
on Avenue Trudaine, Paris 9
returning from
his best friend's funeral
Eugene Colere erased him
from his address book.
At the same moment,
a sperm with one X chromosome
belonging to Raphael Poulain
made a dash for an egg
in his wife Amandine.
Nine months later
Amelie Poulain was born.
AMELIE FROM MONTMARTRE
Her father,
an ex-Army doctor
works at a spa
at Enghien Les Bains.
TIGHT LIPS, HARD HEART
Raphael Poulain dislikes
peeing next to someone else.
He also dislikes
catching scornful glances
at his sandals
clingy wet swimming trunks.
Raphael Poulain likes
peeling large strips
of wallpaper
lining up
and shining his shoes
emptying his toolbox
cleaning it out
and putting
everything back.
Amelie's mother
a schoolmistress
from Grugeon
has always had shaky nerves.
FACIAL TWITCH, WEAK NERVES
She dislikes puckered fingers
in the bath
having her hands
touched by strangers
pillow marks on her cheek
in the morning.
Amandine Poulain likes figure
skaters' costumes on TV
polishing the parquet
emptying her handbag
cleaning it out
and putting
everything back.
Amelie is six.
Like all little girls, she'd
like to be hugged by her Daddy.
But he never touches her,
except for a monthly checkup.
The thrill
of this rare contact
makes her heart
beat like a drum.
As a result, he thinks
she has a heart defect.
Declared unfit for school
Amelie is taught by her mother.
The hens brood here henceforth.
- Four hens brood
- Very good.
- Hens fourth.
- No!
Deprived of playmates
slung between
a neurotic and an iceberg
Amelie retreats
into her imagination.
In this world,
LPs are made like pancakes.
The neighbor's comatose wife
has chosen to get
all her life's sleep in one go.
After this, I can stay awake
day and night.
Amelie has one friend, Blubber.
Alas, the home environment
has made Blubber suicidal.
Blubber's suicide attempts
destroy Mother's nerves.
A decision is made.
Enough!
To comfort Amelie, her mother
gives her a used Instamatic.
Little girl, look what you did!
A neighbor fools her
into thinking her camera
causes accidents.
Having taken pictures
all afternoon
Amelie is petrified.
She stares at the TV,
racked by the guilt
of causing a huge fire
two derailments
a jumbo jet crash.
A few days later
realizing she'd been had
Amelie gets her revenge.
What?!
One day, tragedy strikes.
Amandine takes Amelie
to Notre Dame
to pray for a baby brother.
Minutes later, heaven sends
alas, not a baby boy
but Marguerite,
a tourist from Quebec
bent on ending her life.
Amandine dies instantly.
After her mother's death
Amelie lives alone
with her father.
His unsociable tendencies
increase.
He's obsessed with building
a miniature shrine
to house his wife's ashes.
Days, months, and years go by.
In such a dead world,
Amelie prefers to dream
she'll earn enough
to leave home.
Five years later, she's
a waitress in Montmartre
at the Two Windmills.
It's August 29th.
In 48 hours, her life
will change forever
but she doesn't know it yet.
She lives quietly among
her coworkers and regulars.
Suzanne, the owner
limps a little
but never spills a drink.
A former bareback artiste,
she likes
athletes who cry
with disappointment.
She dislikes seeing men
humiliated
in front of their kids.
Georgette, the tobacconist,
is a hypochondriac
migraines one day,
sciatica the next.
She hates the words,
"fruit of thy womb."
Gina works with Amelie.
Her grandma was a healer.
She likes cracking bones.
She brings a kir to Hipolito,
a failed writer.
He likes seeing bullfighters
gored on TV.
Scowling at them is Joseph,
Gina's rejected lover.
He's always jealously
spying on her.
All he likes
is popping bubble wrap.
Here's Philomene,
an air hostess.
Amelie keeps her cat
when she's away.
Philomene likes
the sound of the cat's bowl
on the tiles.
The cat likes overhearing
children's stories.
No, thanks, ma'am.
I never work Sundays.
On weekends, Amelie often takes
a train to see her father.
- Why not use your retirement?
- To do what?
Travel.
You've never been away.
When we were young, your mother
and I longed to travel.
We couldn't,
because of your heart.
I know.
So, now
Now
Some Fridays,
Amelie sees a movie.
I like looking back
at people's faces in the dark.
I like noticing details
that no one else sees
but I hate it in old movies
when drivers
don't watch the road.
You know, you're
a very beautiful woman, Ellie.
- Why, Stan!
- A very, very beautiful woman.
Amelie has no boyfriend.
She tried once or twice,
but the results were a letdown.
Instead, she cultivates
a taste for small pleasures:
Dipping her hand
into sacks of grain
cracking crème brulee
with a teaspoon
and skipping stones
at St. Martin's Canal.
They call him "the Glass Man."
He was born with bones
as brittle as crystal.
All his furniture is padded.
A handshake
could crush his fingers.
He's stayed inside
for twenty years.
Time has changed nothing.
Amelie still seeks solitude.
She amuses herself
with silly questions
about the world below
such as, "how many couples
are having an orgasm now?"
Fifteen!
Finally, on August 30, 1997
comes the event
that changes her life forever.
Lady Di,
Princess of Wales
died in a car crash
last night
with her companion
Dodi Al-Fayed.
Only the discoverer
of Tutankhamen's tomb
would know how she felt
upon finding this treasure
hidden by a little boy
40 years ago.
On August 31 st at 4:00 a. M
Amelie had a dazzling idea.
Wherever he was, she would
find the box's owner
and give him back his treasure.
If he was touched, she'd
become a regular do-gooder.
If not, too bad.
The girl from the fifth floor.
We don't see much of you.
Would you know of a boy who
lived in my flat in the Fifties?
A boy?
Have a glass of port.
- No, thanks.
- Come in! Close the door.
Boys? I've known so many.
They're cute
until they discover
snowballs and chestnuts.
I've known so many boys.
When did you come here?
In '64.
You'll have heard the story?
No.
I'm amazed. Sit down.
My husband worked
for Ladybird Insurance.
It's no secret
he slept with his secretary.
They used every hotel around.
Not cheap ones, either.
The bimbo
liked spreading her legs
but only on satin
so he swiped from the till
a little at first,
then 50 million.
Off they flew to Panama.
Drink up.
On January 20, 1970
my doorbell rang.
"Your husband's been killed in
a car crash in South America."
My life stopped there.
Black Lion died of heartbreak.
Poor creature.
See how lovingly
he stares at his master?
I'll read you his letters.
Don't go!
You can spare 5 minutes.
He wrote this
from the Army camp.
"Darling Mado"
That's me Madeleine.
"I can't sleep, can't eat
"knowing that my only reason
to live is far away in Paris
"and I won't see her
until next Friday
"when my sweet little weasel
appears at the station
"in her blue dress."
In brackets"the one
you think is too transparent."
Did anyone ever write you
like that?
I'm nobody's little weasel.
My name is Madeleine Wells.
Madeleine,
like Mary Magdalene.
She wept, right?
Wells, as in water.
Talk about being born to cry!
About your question
ask Collignon, the grocer.
He's lived here all his life.
Hello, Amelie-mellow!
A fig and three nuts, as usual?
Who lived in my flat
in the Fifties?
What was their name?
You've got me there, dear.
In 1950, I was two
the mental age of a cretin.
The "cretin" is Lucien.
He's no genius,
but Amelie likes him.
She likes the way
he handles each endive
like a precious object
to be treated with care.
It's his way of showing
his love of good work.
Look at him!
Like he's nursing a baby bird!
Don't ask him for currants.
You'd be here till Monday!
Get moving, spastic!
She hasn't got all day!
Go see my mother.
She has an elephant's memory.
Elephant mom!
Thank you.
Bredoteau.
Pardon?
The name you're after.
But if I say it, it won't count.
I'm senile.
Ignore him. He's senile.
See what he's done
to my laurel?
His old job
was punching metro tickets.
Now he gets up every night
to punch holes in my laurel!
Too bad it's not hardy.
We all need a way to relax.
I skip stones.
- You do?
- I'll find it, don't worry.
I'm very organized.
- I like everything.
- Like what?
Your son's nearly fifty,
and I'm still doing
his bookkeeping!
You were still squeezing
his toothpaste at fifteen.
- It follows.
- Camus
second floor,
Broussard was on B block
Got it!
Bredoteau, fifth floor.
They were northerners.
Bredoteau.
What more I can say?
How could I live
Never to know the joy
that you give
When I'm in your arms
I'm under your charms
How could I live
Without you
Groping under the photo booth
is Nino Quincampoix.
When Amelie lacked playmates,
Nino had too many.
Five miles apart,
they both dreamed
of having
a brother and sister
to be with all the time.
Hi, Dad.
A new friend?
I've had him for years.
Your mother hated him,
so he lived in the tool shed.
There. Let's reconcile them.
There. How about that?
Dad, if you found a precious
relic from your childhood
how would you feel?
Happy? Sad? Nostalgic?
This gnome isn't a relic.
He was a retirement gift
from my old regiment.
No, I mean something you hid,
like a secret treasure.
I should varnish him
before the autumn.
I'll make some tea.
You want some?
Breathe in. Hold still.
Better now?
Shut the door!
There's a howling gale.
It's not Siberia.
You're not allergic
to car fumes!
I almost coughed up my pleura
last night.
Cough up a pleura?
- What's on today, Suzanne?
- Endives au gratin.
They'll have you on your knees.
That's good?
- Depends where you fall.
- Lf in front of the toilet
Not good.
12:15 laughs orgasmically
to attract alpha male.
He's gonna drive me berserk.
Can't he give up?
There are plenty of other bars!
Good-bye.
Madame Suzanne?
"Au gratin"
means white sauce, right?
Yes. Why?
I can't stomach it,
like you and horse meat.
It's not my stomach,
it's my memory.
I'd rather cook human flesh.
You're kidding.
Madame Suzanne,
can I leave early today?
What's his name?
Dominique Bredoteau.
Hello.
You're Dominique Bredoteau?
That's me.
Why?
It's about the petition.
Petition?
Yes. The petition to
to canonize Lady Di!
No, thanks.
No.
Ladies and gentlemen
sorry to bother you
Yes?
Hello. I'm looking
for Dominique Bredoteau
for the European census.
Come up, third floor.
Hello, kitten.
Earl Grey?
Jasmine?
What will you have?
I'm busy.
Here. Coming!
Where can I find
Dominique Bredoteau?
Poor dear! You just missed him.
Look, there he goes now.
Bretod-eau.
Not Bredot-eau.
You need a little mulled wine.
Come in.
I've lived here for five years.
I never saw you before.
I never go out on the landing.
I'm fussy about who I meet.
They're all bums.
Come in.
They call me the Glass Man
but my name is Raymond Dufayel.
Amelie Poulain.
I'm a waitress at
The Two Windmills. I know.
And right now,
your Bredoteau basket is empty.
Because it's not "do."
It's "to."
Like "Toto."
I love that painting.
It's the Luncheon
of the Boating Party.
By Renoir.
I've painted one each year
for twenty years.
The hardest part is the looks.
I sometimes feel like
they deliberately change
their mood behind my back.
They look quite happy.
They should be!
They're eating hare
with morels
and waffles with jam
for the kids.
Now, where's
that piece of paper?
You've noticed my video camera.
A gift from my sister-in-law.
I put it there
so I don't need
to wind up my clocks.
After all these years
the only person
I still can't capture
is the girl
with the glass of water.
She's in the middle,
yet she's outside.
Maybe she's just different.
In what way?
I don't know.
When she was little, she rarely
played with other kids.
Maybe never.
Dominique
Dominique Bretodeau,
27 Rue Mouffetard.
It's for you.
Every Tuesday morning
Dominique Bretodeau
buys a chicken.
He roasts it with potatoes.
After carving
the legs and wings
he loves picking the hot carcass
with his fingers
starting with the oysters.
But not today.
Bretodeau won't buy a chicken.
He'll go no further
than this phone booth here.
In a flash, it all came back
Bahamontes
winning the Tour de France.
Aunt Josette's slips.
And most of all,
the tragic day
The day he won all the marbles.
The pinch, Bretodeau!
Bretodeau,
does he know what it is?
Cognac, please.
Amazing, what just happened.
It must be my guardian angel.
The phone booth
was calling me
Same here!
The microwave's calling me.
I'll have another cognac.
Life's funny.
To a kid, time always drags.
Suddenly you're fifty.
All that's left
of your childhood
fits in a rusty little box.
You got kids, Miss?
I have a daughter
about your age.
We haven't spoken for years.
I heard she had a child, a boy.
His name is Lucas.
It's time I looked them up,
before I'm in a box myself.
Don't you think?
Amelie has a strange feeling
of absolute harmony.
It's a perfect moment.
Soft light
a scent in the air,
the quiet murmur of the city.
She breathes deeply.
Life is simple and clear.
A surge of love, an urge
to help mankind comes over her.
Let me help you.
Step down. Here we go!
The drum major's widow!
She's worn his coat
since the day he died.
The horse's head
has lost an ear!
That's the florist laughing.
He has crinkly eyes.
In the bakery window, lollipops.
Smell that!
They're giving out melon slices.
Sugarplum ice cream!
We're passing the park butcher.
Ham, 79 francs.
Spareribs, 45!
Now the cheese shop. Picadors
are 12.90. Cabecaus 23.50.
A baby's watching a dog
that's watching the chickens.
Now we're at the kiosk
by the metro.
I'll leave you here. Bye!
"She can't relate
to other people."
"She was always a lonely child."
On a sparkling evening
in July
while on the beaches,
holiday hordes
relax in the new-found sun
and Paris's
sweltering denizens
gaze at the star bursts
of the traditional fireworks
Amelie Poulain
Godmother of Outcasts,
Madonna of the Unloved
finally succumbed to exhaustion.
In Paris's stricken streets
a countless throng
of mourners
lined her funeral route
in silence
with the measureless grief
of newly orphaned children.
What a strange destiny
for one who gave her all
yet took such joy
in life's simple pleasures.
Like Don Quixote,
she pitted herself
against the grinding windmills
of all life's miseries.
It was a losing battle
that claimed her life too soon.
At barely 23, Amelie Poulain
let her young, tired body
merge
with the ebb and flow
of universal woe.
As she went,
she felt a stab of regret
for letting her father die
without trying
to give his stifled life
the breath of air
she had given
to so many others.
Wait!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Wait! Wait!
Pages full of dual ID photos
torn up and discarded
by their owners
carefully reassembled
by some oddball.
Some family album!
A pack of Gaulaises.
Just a second.
It's so smoky in here.
Where are they?
I can't see a thing.
More to the left.
More
You need change.
Forget it.
A mauresque for the young man.
One kir, one mauresque,
and two mint sodas.
Was that prenuptial
or post-smooching?
Are you a congenital schmuck?
- Prenuptial.
- Don't worry.
You'll find your Mr. Right
one day.
All women want to sleep
on a man's shoulder.
All men snore
after a few drinks
and I have a musical ear.
I had my nasal cavities fixed.
I see you're a born romantic.
I see you've never known
true love.
I did. It shortened my leg.
I thought you fell off a horse.
I did.
I was in love
with a trapeze artist.
Stupid me. They always
drop you at the last minute.
He dropped me
just before my act.
It floored me.
Plus the horse
with me under it.
The mauresque?
Still, true love does exist.
I know.
After 30 years behind a bar
I'm an expert.
I'll even give you the recipe.
Take two regulars
mix them together
and let them stew.
It never fails.
Excuse me!
I'll go.
Haven't you hurt enough people?
Gina can defend herself.
I don't mean Gina.
I mean Georgette.
Look!
She craves your attention
but all you can see is Gina.
Poor girl!
The things she does
to catch your eye!
You really must be blind.
I'm off on a date. Bye!
Whoever her new one is
he can't be worse than that nut
with his tape recorder.
Joseph's not so nutty.
He's just in pain.
Come on!
They split up two months ago.
To keep on coming here,
he must be a masochist.
Don't say you haven't noticed.
Noticed what?
Well, he always
sits here, right?
At number 8?
Sit down.
Sit down, Georgette.
What can you see?
My cigarette counter.
Nothing's missing?
Well, no.
Make an effort.
I can't see what!
Think about it. Good night.
Letter Arrives 30 Years Late.
A mailbag found by climbers
on a glacier on Mont Blanc
was part of a cargo
lost in a plane crash
in the late 1960s.
So sad. A young,
pretty princess for once.
It's OK if she's old and ugly?
Sure! Look at Mother Teresa.
Is he still chasing Gina?
No, he has somebody else.
Anyone I know?
Funny about this glacier
Somebody at the Two Windmills?
Not you!
Not Suzanne
- No!
- Yes.
There he is again.
How strange.
- And here.
- "Him again!"
"Lyon Station."
And here.
"March 5, Austerlitz."
Always the same blank face.
Always neutral.
Twelve times.
I counted. It's very odd.
Why keep taking your picture
all over town
and throw them away?
Good one, too.
It's like a ritual.
He's probably terrified
of growing old.
It's his only consolation.
He's dead!
He's scared of being forgotten.
He wants to remind people
of his face.
Like faxing his portrait
from the afterlife.
A dead man
scared of being forgotten.
These guys here
have it made!
They're long dead
but they'll never be forgotten.
The girl with the glass
Maybe her thoughts
are with somebody else.
Somebody in the picture?
More likely a boy
she saw somewhere
and felt an affinity with.
You mean she'd rather
imagine herself
relating to an absent person
than build relationships
with those around her?
Maybe she tries hard to fix
other people's messy lives.
What about her?
Her own messy life?
Who'll fix that?
It's better to help people
than a garden gnome.
The trucker had 2.8 grams
of alcohol in his blood!
Makes me sick.
Talk about employing
irresponsible morons!
- Your keys.
- Hold on, Mello.
Speed kills nowadays.
Model yourself on Lucien.
No radar will ever catch him
while he's working!
Shame on you, Mr. Collignon.
It's not his fault.
True, Mrs. Couchoix.
It's not his fault
he can't sleep.
It's Lady Di's.
Guess what I found
in the truck?
A lingerie catalog.
He'd pasted Lady Di's face
over the model's!
What today?
Five asparagus
or more local history?
Nothing.
KEYS CUT WHILE YOU WAIT
The migraine's better?
Yes, but my sciatica
kept me awake all night.
It's ages since I saw you
looking so good.
Oh, yeah?
"A woman without love wilts
like a flower without sun."
Strange weather today!
What's so funny?
You're only the 100th one
to say it.
We pass the time of day
to forget how time passes.
We do it to keep
from taking crap.
I write crap
that nobody publishes.
- Another rejection?
- My 30th!
Isn't your cousin a book critic?
Forget it!
Critics are like leeches
sucking the blood of writers.
Is your book
a love story?
It's about a guy
who keeps a journal.
Not about his past
but about disasters
in his future.
So he gets depressed
and does nothing.
Basically, it's about a loafer.
I'll dedicate
the manuscript to you.
So you'll write off his tab.
His scribbles for my nibbles.
That's sponsorship.
What took you so long?
Look at the time!
Somebody peed in his mother!
FOOT CREAM
TOOTHPASTE
"Without you,
today's emotions
"would be the scurf
of yesterday's."
"Without you,
today's emotion's
"would be the scurf
of yesterday's."
Without you,
today's emotions
would be the scurf
of yesterday's.
Tickets, please.
How's work?
You asked me already.
You OK these days?
Pretty much.
I feel a change.
I had two heart attacks,
an abortion, did crack
while I was pregnant.
Other than that, I'm fine.
Good.
Something wrong?
No, nothing.
Your gnome's gone.
Is he back in the tool shed?
Moscow.
There. See?
No explanation.
He wants to see the world?
I can't understand it.
LOST
BAG
PHOTOS
Any normal girl
would call the number
meet him, return the album
and see if her dream is viable.
It's called a reality check.
The last thing Amelie wants.
I say!
Could she be falling in love?
Where's the boss?
Sleeping in the cauliflower.
What?
You want me want what?
A scratch card, please.
How does it work?
Tell you what.
Let's both do one together.
You scratch it here
sideways.
Nothing. You?
Me, neither.
Unlucky at cards
So they say.
I have to get back.
Yes.
Porno Video Palace.
I'm calling about the ad.
- You're over 18?
- Yes.
- Shaved?
- Sorry?
Are you shaved?
Fur pie doesn't sell.
How's life, Mrs. Wells?
When you've nothing
to live for
Come on, life's great!
Dream on, kid.
Hello, Mr. Dufayel.
Here's your order, Mr. Dufayel.
I doubt it. I hate artichokes.
You shouldn't. Watch this.
Take it.
That's better.
Lucien, you're a wizard!
Courtesy of Mr. Collignon.
Mister Collignon?
Sorry, it slipped out.
Practice, Lucien!
Practice! Repeat after me.
Collignon, down the john.
Your turn now. Collignon
Collignon, big moron!
See? You can do it.
Collignon, dead and gone!
Very good!
Collignon, big moron,
down the john!
OK! That's enough for today.
Lucien, that's enough!
Very good.
I found this under your mat.
Still no win!
Me, neither.
May I?
There's a little
You're gorgeous when you blush.
Like a wild flower.
It's my dyspepsia.
Morning, all!
Beautiful day.
Pack of Gitanes, please.
Bravo! Vive la France!
You scalded me!
Ten out of ten! Bull's-eye!
It was Amelie, she
When they went up Mont Blanc
the silicon in her face
froze up.
Her face was a festering mass!
Mulled wine and spice cookies.
I was too hard on the girl
with the glass.
Tell me about that boy she saw.
Did they meet again?
They're into different things.
Luck is like the Tour de France.
You wait,
and it flashes past you.
You have to catch it
while you can.
Can I help you?
Excuse me.
I found this in the street.
Nino will be glad!
He was so sad the other day.
I almost prayed to St. Anthony!
Is Nino here now?
On Wednesdays
he works at the funfair.
How long has
he had this collection?
Since I got him the job here,
last year.
Before, he collected footprints.
He worked nights.
In the daytime, he took pictures
of footprints in wet cement.
He's a funny guy.
When we met,
he was a Santa Claus.
Other things, like
whenever he heard a funny laugh,
he'd tape it.
Gosh!
Must be hard for his girlfriend.
He never keeps them long.
Times are hard for dreamers.
Eva! Are those coffees coming?
Gotta go. Thanks for the album.
It's OK. I have time
to take it to the funfair.
Suit yourself. The Ghost Train.
Ask for Nino Quincompoix.
Is Nino here?
He doesn't get in till 7:00.
Is there no way
to see him before?
Sure. 20 francs.
See you next Wednesday.
5 p.m. Tomorrow,
Montmartre carousel.
Bring 5 francs.
Want to know about her?
- You know her?
- You bet!
She put us in her shirt pocket.
Next to her breast.
- Is she pretty?
- Not bad.
- Beautiful.
- No. Pretty.
- Beautiful!
- Pretty.
- What does she want from me?
- She's broke.
She wants a reward
for the album.
Or else
she collects photos, too.
She wants to trade us for
a one-eyed man with glasses!
No, you dope!
She's in love.
- I don't even know her.
- You do.
Since when?
Since always.
In your dreams.
You! Man with the plastic bag!
It's for you.
Follow the blue arrows,
Mr. Quincompoix.
The fool looks at a finger
that points at the sky
I know the stranger
in the pictures.
He's a ghost. He's invisible!
He only appears
when the film is developed.
When a girl
has her photo taken
he goes "Wooo!" in her ear
while he fondles her neck.
That's how he got caught,
Mr. Quincompoix!
Who are you?
Page St.
DO YOU
WANT
TO MEET ME?
Listen to this. "Boy of 6,
while parents sleep
"drives off in a pedal car.
"Found on a highway
in Germany
"he told police
he wanted to see the stars."
Ain't life beautiful, though?
Love.
The only bug she hadn't caught.
- Nobody's immune.
- It gives me a break.
Love's a great beautician.
What's she like?
Tall, small? Fair, dark?
Let's say average height.
Not a dwarf or a giraffe.
Normal.
Pretty, for her type.
As for fair or dark,
it's hard to say.
She wasn't a redhead.
Unless
Forget it.
I remember she casually asked
about your girlfriend.
And?
I said you weren't interested,
right?
You didn't!
What do you care?
You don't even know her.
- Exactly. It's the mystery.
- You won't find mystery here.
A pound of nectarines.
The ones here
are the prettiest.
Trust him. He's an artist.
He goes home
with a ton of unsold stock.
What for? Is he stewing a pig?
No, sir! He's studying art!
Sells leeks all day long
and paints turnips all night!
The boy's a useless vegetable!
With a prompter
in each cellar window
whispering comebacks
shy people
would have the last laugh.
At least
you'll never be a vegetable!
Even artichokes have hearts.
You'll never be a vegetable.
Even artichokes have hearts!
"Darling Mado, I miss you
more and more each day.
"I'm an exile
in a world of dreary khaki.
"I can't sleep, can't eat
"This camp was
the mistake of my life
"depriving me of my beloved
for five long weeks.
"I think of you endlessly.
Your Adrien."
"I turned down my last month's
wages instead of giving notice.
"I dream of better times ahead.
"An orange-colored day.
Remember, my love?
"Your everloving Adrien."
"Good news, sweetheart.
"Soon I'll be able
to afford a car
"and drive home every night.
"Till then, meet me on Friday,
and we'll go out."
MOTHER
Psychiatric Helpline.
WHERE & WHEN?
One hour later,
on Boulevard St. Martin
Amelie walks into a party goods
and costume shop.
At the same time, a man leaves
his home on Rue Lecourbe.
26 minutes later,
Amelie is at East Station.
Simultaneously, the man
in red shoes parks outside.
The time is exactly 11:40.
At this precise moment
only Amelie has the key to
the riddle of the mystery man.
How's it going, Mrs. Wells?
Not so bad
when it's not raining.
- This is for you.
- Me?
"Dear Mrs. Wells, we recently
recovered a mailbag
"that was lost
in a plane crash
"on October 12th, 1969,
on Mont Blanc.
"We are forwarding the enclosed
letter to your address
"with our apologies
for the uncustomary delay.
"Jacques Grasjeau,
Customer Services."
"Darling Mado, I'm in exile.
I can't sleep, can't eat
"I think of you endlessly.
"I know I've made
the mistake of my life.
"I turned down
that woman's money.
"If all goes well, I'll soon be
able to afford a house.
"I dream of
better times ahead
"when you'll forgive me
and join me here
"one orange-colored day.
Your everloving Adrien."
Another package for you.
You heard about the concierge?
She got a letter.
From her husband, 40 years late.
That's a lot, isn't it?
I'm not big on still life,
Mr. Dufayel.
Then work on your lean layer.
Fat over lean. Always!
I heard
there'll soon be a new star.
You're into stars now?
I saw it on TV at my ma's,
that's why.
I dunno if it's true.
In America
they'll take
rich people's ashes
put them in a satellite
and shoot it into space.
It's going to shine forever.
And Lady Di
will they do the same for her?
Lady Di! Lady Di!
Give it a rest!
I can't concentrate!
Lady Di! Lady Di!
Renoir!
I don't understand.
Brilliant! You were perfect.
Did it work?
It's getting there.
Ask me again anytime.
The harm's done.
- Harm?
- Everybody calls me Snow White!
The Two Windmills at 4 p.m.
Could you stand in for me
at 4:00?
Again?
What's eating him?
- I smile too much.
- He'd rather you frowned?
With other men, yes.
Nino is late. Amelie can
only see two explanations.
1 He didn't get the photo.
2 Before he could
assemble it
a gang of bank robbers
took him hostage.
The cops gave chase.
They got away
but he caused a crash.
When he came to,
he'd lost his memory.
An ex-con picked him up
mistook him for a fugitive
and shipped him to Istanbul.
There he met
some Afghan raiders
who took him to steal
some Russian warheads.
But their truck hit a mine
in Tajikistan.
He survived,
took to the hills
and became a Mujaheddin.
Amelie refuses
to get upset for a guy
who'll eat borscht all his life
in a hat like a tea cozy.
- What can I get you?
- Coffee, please.
TODAY'S MENU
He's understood.
He's going to put down
his spoon
dip his finger in the sugar
turn around slowly
and speak to me.
Is this you?
Yes, it's you.
- More coffee?
- No thanks.
So it's this man here,
with his hand up?
Is she in love with him?
I think it's time
she took a real risk.
She might.
She's devising a stratagem.
She's fond of stratagems.
In fact, she's cowardly.
That's why
I can't capture her look.
Dufayel's attempts to meddle
are intolerable!
If Amelie chooses
to live in a dream
and remain
an introverted young woman
she has an absolute right
to mess up her life!
What are you doing?
Tell me, Lucien.
For deliveries, do you keep
keys to all the apartments?
One of your booths
is out of order.
It seems to be jammed.
East Station ticket hall.
Buy a video, get one free?
Samantha?
Can you stand in for me at
Photo booth. East Station.
Tuesday 5 p.m.
Almost done.
The mystery man wasn't a ghost
or a man scared of aging
but simply the repairman
a normal technician
doing his work.
He keeps spying on me.
It's making me sick.
4:05: Blatant female conspiracy.
Gosh, you're tense!
Good luck. You'll need it.
Excuse me.
Did you put this in my pocket?
- Yes, but it's not from me.
- I know. Where is she?
She's at her father's.
It bothers me.
Can I talk to you?
I get off at 6:00.
- Can you come back?
- OK.
See you then.
4:08: Docking scheduled.
A blond guy in a camel coat.
Absent-minded, too.
How come?
He came back
three times the same day.
1:12
Camel coat.
2:50
- 4:17.
- Stop it!
My rash has come back!
Look. Suzanne!
My rash is back.
He's driving me nuts!
Lay off!
Her conscience is at fault.
I've had it! I'm going home.
Psychos are the last straw!
Stop smothering them.
Women need air.
You give them air,
they blow you off.
Fresh air's healthy.
Cram it, failure!
Failed writer, failed life
I love the word "fail."
Failure is human destiny.
It's gasbag time!
Failure teaches us
that life is but a draft
a long rehearsal for a show
that will never play.
I bet he stole that.
I do have some original ideas
but people always steal them.
Same as your women.
Meaning?
You'd better get used to it.
Speak for yourself, you
- What's going on?
- Nothing much.
Georgette went out,
Joseph got mad.
"Went out"?
Like Gina.
You know who Gina's with?
The guy with the plastic bag!
I saw their little game.
The note in the coat pocket.
4:08.
Back he comes, and hey presto!
Out they go.
I'm worried for Amelie
because I like you.
What do you mean?
By and large, the men I like
are mentally unsound.
I'd like to know more
about you.
Ask me.
One swallow doesn't make?
A swallow?
A summer.
Practice makes
Perfect.
- Curiosity
- Killed the cat.
- Haste
- Makes waste.
- Rolling stone
- Gathers no moss.
- It's a sin
- To steal a pin.
- Absence makes
- The heart grow fonder.
- Not bad.
- You collect them?
At home, we say a man who knows
proverbs can't be all bad.
Pretty girl from
the fifth floor, listen to this!
- You believe in miracles?
- Not today.
You're in for a surprise.
What if I told you
that a team of climbers
on Mont Blanc had found
hard proof
that my husband loved me?
Lucien, I need some yeast.
For Miss Amelie? She's baking
her famous plum cake?
Collignon! Go!
I'll be right back.
I'll be back.
Go into the bedroom,
Miss Poulain.
So, little Amelie
your bones aren't made of glass.
You can take life's knocks.
If you let this chance go by
eventually,
your heart will become
as dry and brittle
as my skeleton.
So
go get him, for Pete's sake!
"Without you,
today's emotions
"would be the scurf
of yesterday's."
International airport.
September 28, 1997.
It is exactly 11 a.m.
At the funfair,
near the ghost train
the marshmallow twister's
twisting
while in Villette Park,
Felix Lerbier
learns there are more links
in his brain
than atoms in the universe.
At the Sacre Coeur
the Cardinals are practicing
their backhands.
The temperature
is 24 degrees Celsius.
Humidity, 70%.
Atmospheric pressure,
999 millibars.
}
www.moviesubtitles.org