C.M.I. Presents
THE WHITE BALLOON
Script: Abbas Kiarostami
From an original idea
by Parviz Shahbazi
Starring: F. Sadr Orfani
A. Bourkowska
Aïda Mohammadkhani
Mohsen Kafili
Mohammad Bakhtiari
Mohammad Shahani
Unit Manager: Mehran Rassam
Assistant Cameraman:
Mahmoud Heydari
Stills Photographer: Fatemeh Taamidi
Titles: Zabiholah Asgari
Assistant Unit Manager:
Behrouz Hamed Saberi
Assistant Director:
Parviz Shahbazi
Mixing Engineer:
Mehdi Dejbodi
Sound Engineers:
M. Mortazavi, S. Ahmadi
Executive Producer:
Ferdos Film Company
Production Manager:
Kourosh Mazkouri
Director of Photography:
Farzad Jowdat
Set design, editing and direction:
Jafar Panahi
Dear listeners,
we wish you a nice day.
It is now 7 minutes past 5.
We have exactly
1 hour, 28 minutes
and 30 seconds
before the New Year.
Is this gentleman wrong then?
Yes, he is talking nonsense.
Can I ask you one more question?
Whatever you want!
Can you extract this animal's sting?
It doesn't have one, my friend!
It's not a wasp, nor a scorpion!
- So a snake doesn't have a sting?
- No, it has teeth!
- Poisonous teeth?
- Of course!
Now that you know
that a snake has poisonous teeth,
you also know that
all of these snakes are dangerous.
So with your permission,
I will tell you a poem
while I'm taking
the horned snake out.
I'll show its horns
to those who are curious.
Come on!
But don't think that a snake's horn
is like that of a deer.
It's not like the horn
of a deer, nor that of a goat.
It's like two grains of rice
on both sides of its head,
and they are called the snake's horns.
Mum, let me go buy one...
I'll be back in no time.
I said no.
- Leave it open.
- Too late.
- Where are you going?
- To buy soap for Dad.
- Please let me go buy it.
- I said no.
Look in the basin. Where do you
think they get them from?
Every year, they used to take ours,
but not this year.
It's the same goldfish
that they sell in the market.
I'll come back quickly.
I won't get lost, I promise.
I saw them myself.
They are different.
Ours are skinny.
What did you say?
There is not even
a drop of shampoo left!
I wasn't talking to you!
Believe me, they are not the same.
Ours are so skinny!
Skinny!
You're not going to eat them!
It looks like they are dancing
when they move their fins.
Their fins are long.
They have four of them!
Enough. I have a lot of work to do.
Put the basket away
and get the flower pot.
But there were only 3 left.
They will be all gone
if we don't buy one right away.
We won't have any for the New Year
and we won't have any
when Granny comes.
And of course we can't celebrate
the New Year without the goldfish!
Don't sit in a corner.
Come and catch one of these.
Get the strainer
as well as your bowl.
Come on, get going.
Mum, please let me go.
I'll give you all my gifts instead.
You haven't got any gifts yet!
I'll get gifts from Granny.
I'll give them all to you.
Not only have you put your
new clothes on before New Year
but you've also given your gifts away
before getting them!
What's the matter?
Nothing. She's just making a fuss.
Hurry up.
If you pick up your mother late
like last year,
it'll be my fault again.
Stop whining on New Year's Eve
or you'll be crying
all year long.
Go catch a goldfish.
Take your strainer
and wash the goldfish bowl.
Come on.
- Dad!
- What is it?
- I got it.
- It's about time!
Put the basket in the room
and the fruit next to the basin.
The bag just ripped.
You're whining again!
Mum refuses to give me money
for the goldfish.
Don't you like ours?
You call these goldfish,
you haven't seen the others!
It's as though they're dancing
when they move their fins.
- And they've got so many fins!
- How much?
- The shopkeeper said 100 tomans.
- 100 tomans!
You want to pay 100 tomans
for a goldfish!
You can watch two films
with that money!
You're nuts!
I tell you shampoo
and you come back with soap!
You never pay attention.
Did you make him yell?
You do whatever you like!
I thought he said soap, not shampoo.
His voice echoes.
You can't hear him from here.
Take the soap out of water
and dry it.
Zahra!
Do you want egg shampoo?
Yes, egg shampoo.
- Here, hurry up.
- Shall I get shampoo then?
Yes.
You're still there?
You want to get on his nerves again?
- Hi Reza, how are you?
- Fine, thanks.
How's your mother?
She sent me to ask you
for a goldfish.
It's for our New Year's decoration.
You tell my Razieh:
Aren't these the same fish
as the New Year's goldfish?
Yes.
Aren't they the same
as the ones in the market?
- Yes.
- You see!
Where exactly did your mother
tell you to get them from?
From you.
You see!
You never believe what I say.
Go ahead, Reza.
Catch one for her as well.
Did you get one?
Wonderful, isn't it?
These are skinny,
but the others are chubby.
The shopkeeper said 100 only.
You mean we can't even pay that?
I don't believe it!
The others get their goldfish from us
and you want to get yours
from the market!
We have better things to do!
This is all you get.
Hurry up.
Don't forget to wash the strainer.
- What is it now?
- The water is cold!
I'm coming.
Go check if the water-heater
is working properly.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye. Did you catch a few?
- Yes.
How many did you get?
Dad, I got the shampoo.
- What are you holding?
- A letter for the neighbours.
- Where from?
- Mashhad.
Slide it under their door
and get on with what you have to do.
Dear listeners, it's exactly
5 o'clock, 18 minutes and 21 seconds.
How many fish did
Reza the carrot-top catch?
We have 1 hour, 15 minutes
and 9 seconds left to the New Year.
Happy New Year to you all.
Go see if the water-heater
is still on.
OK, I'll see.
Here, this is for you.
- What do you want in exchange?
- Nothing.
Oh, come on. You never give
anything away like that!
Look how skinny it is.
The ones in the market are different.
They are prettier.
There were only 3 left. If we don't
buy one, they'II all be gone.
You only give me this balloon
in exchange for the fish?
What do you want?
- The one Uncle gave you.
- Which one?
- The one he brought last time.
- No.
- Ali!
- What is it?
- Bring me the oil can.
- Right away.
So, will you give it to me?
OK.
All right, wait a little bit.
Pour the oil in there.
Close the tap, the heater is off.
Open it now.
Did you open it?
I said no.
Go ahead, open it.
Is it OK now?
You haven't polished
your father's shoes yet?
Polish yours as well.
You promised to buy
new shoes for me.
I'll get them for you.
Polish them for now.
Prices are high before the New Year.
You want me to polish these as well?
I'll repair them for you.
They'II look like new again.
Don't be a pain like your sister!
I haven't got anything left.
The money is all gone.
I've just kept a 500-toman note
for the gifts.
Five hundred!
Who do you want to give it to?
No one in particular!
I'll get smaller notes.
So, if people give you money,
I can also give some
to their children.
Wash that too.
You better do what I tell you.
I won't ask you again!
Go on or your father
will get angry again.
Mum!
What now?
I've already said no.
Let me tell you just one thing.
I know what you're going to say
and I've had enough of it!
Just a second, promise me
you won't get angry.
Just a second.
Do as you're told.
If you don't agree,
I won't ask you any more.
All right.
- Come closer.
- Just say it.
I want to whisper it to you.
Come on, say it.
OK, get my bag.
So?
- OK, but don't forget your promise.
- I told you it's yours.
Stay over there.
She mustn't see you.
Check how much money is left.
Two twenties.
What about the small pocket?
A 500 note.
- How much was the goldfish?
- 100.
100 for a fish!
The shopkeeper said they all cost 100.
Without the bowl!
Take the 500 note
and go get one for her.
Give me the towel.
- So, is the balloon mine?
- Yes it is.
- Promise?
- Yes, take it.
- You aren't allowed to go.
- I'll be back soon.
- Be careful not to lose the money.
- OK.
While you're singing,
you'II take out the snake
- which none of these people
have even dreamt of- with this stick.
And while you're showing it to them,
I'll pass the hat around.
God bless anyone
who helps me in these hard times.
Let's see how you
who are sitting around us
help the Dervishes.
This is the first of the four snakes
which I promised to show you.
And in that box, there's another one
which weighs 4 and a quarter kilos.
But these gentlemen might think
that we're not going to show it.
That's not it.
The snake just loves money.
It's not going to come out
until it sees the colour of money.
Dear friends, whether you're Turks,
Persians or Arabs...
Whether you're from the north
or the south, you're all needy
like the Dervish!
There's only one hour left to
the New Year. I'll pass amongst you
and I know
that you'll all be generous.
At least enough for a fish
for my kids' New Year's dinner.
Look at this!
They give expired bank notes
to the Dervish!
Nobody takes these any more,
neither the baker, nor the grocer!
God bless you.
This little girl
has given us a 500 note
for the Dervish's dinner,
for his kids' dinner
and for the Dervish's fish.
It's the proof of her generosity.
She's only 6 or 7 years old.
But thanks to her help,
the Dervish will have
something to eat tonight.
I'm going to take the snake out now.
I'II take it out
and put in the middle
for the New Year
so that everyone can see it.
God bless you all.
You haven't forgotten anything
for the New Year's ceremony!
What a nice bunch of Sabzeh!
- What do you have in your bag?
- It's for New Year.
You've already the fish
for tonight's dinner!
But I know you very well!
You're a respectful man.
Don't waste your time here.
I wanted to watch you,
because I like your act.
God bless you, my friend!
You're in terrific shape! I can see
the chicken you've eaten here
and the turkey there!
Such strong young lads
we have in Iran!
I want my money.
- Sorry?
- I want my money.
- Which money, little angel?
- The money for the fish.
The money for the fish
that the Dervish wanted to eat
with his rice tonight?
You never take back what
you've given! Your money is gone.
My partner has it now.
It's in his pocket.
But I want my money back.
My mother gave me a 500 note
to buy a goldfish.
OK, I see.
My dear Dervish...
What?
The girl's mother
wants her money back.
What do you think of that?
- But she didn't give it to us!
- Who to then?
To this snake, to this penny-pincher!
So we'll put her money here
so that she can come and take it.
Here is the money!
Come get your money, angel.
My dear Dervish!
What'll we do
with this little girl?
Do you have any ideas?
I don't know!
Let's give her a chance
so that she can come
and take her money.
But if she doesn't come quickly,
the snake will wake up
and she won't be able
to take it back!
Did you hear
what the Dervish just said?
Didn't I tell you
this snake is a penny-pincher?
Look here, little girl!
You see, gentlemen,
that the Dervish never lies!
The snake wouldn't peep out
as long as there was no money.
If this girl wants her money,
she must get it herself.
I'll do it myself.
I'll take her money
and give it back to her.
- Sure?
- Sure.
- Won't you regret it?
- No.
How stubborn you can be!
Let her come on her own!
Here sweetie,
come look at the snake.
It's coming out
because of her.
You want it to jump on her?
Who has the guts
to come and take it?
Get back
before somebody gets bitten.
Stop insisting!
Look gentlemen,
wait and see if this snake
is going to let the money go.
Do I look like a liar?
With my white hair
and my old age!
Just wait and see if I was lying!
- What're you going to do now?
- Give the money back to her.
You never listen to me! We'd have
had something to eat tonight!
With whose money
did you want to eat?
That's why your pocket
is always empty!
You didn't expect me
to keep her money?
Don't you see she's crying?
The money is not hers,
it's her mother's.
Here you go, little girl.
This snake likes the colour of money!
See, it doesn't come out
till it sees the money!
I wasn't lying!
My little angel!
Are you afraid of this snake?
It doesn't have teeth!
We just say that to make a living,
to bring some food home.
Look, not even a single tooth.
Don't be scared.
I'II put it in my pocket
so that it doesn't frighten you.
Look.
Is it OK now?
Wipe your tears.
It's all over now.
Nobody should go away after my act
with wet eyes.
Give me a smile and I'II give you
your money. That's a good girl.
Here's your 500 note.
Go. God bless you.
Hi.
Hello. What can I do for you?
I want a goldfish.
Which one do you want?
One of those.
One of the white ones
with plenty of fins.
- You want a big one?
- Yes.
Then it's 200.
But you said yourself
that they cost 100!
Not all of them!
The small ones cost 100,
but the big, pretty ones cost 200.
But since it's you, I'll sell
this little cute one for 100 only!
Hello, madam, welcome!
Feel at home.
So where is your money?
Let me see it.
Can't you give me a big one
for 100 tomans?
No, the big ones cost 200.
How much do you have?
Show me your money.
Come on, take it out.
What've you done with it?
Look in your pocket.
Where did you put it?
I've lost my 500 note!
Where did you lose it?
I'd put it in my goldfish bowl.
- And who has taken it?
- I don't know.
Hey, what's up now?
What's up with you?
I brought 10 earlier.
Here are 5 more.
That makes 15.
- How much did you get earlier?
- 200.
How much more do you want?
250?
Here my boy, there you go.
Now beat it!
Business is hard and on top of that,
this girl is crying.
How much did you have,
little missy?
500 tomans.
You're sure you had a 500 note?
- Yes.
- What did you want to buy with it?
Afish.
What sort of a fish?
One of those in that bowl.
But those don't cost 500!
Maybe you were supposed
to buy a big fish.
No.
But those don't cost that much!
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Can you actually recognize
a 500 note?
Yes.
- What colour is it?
- Red.
Was it like this one?
No.
- So it wasn't this one?
- No.
Wasn't it this one?
No, it was red.
It was red!
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes.
Was it like this one?
- Yes, that's it.
- But this one is mine!
This is my money.
You never gave me a 500 note!
What a day! They gave you
a 500 note to buy a goldfish
and look what a mess you're in now!
Plus, you're wasting my time!
Don't cry.
Go back the way you came
and you'll find your money.
What can I do for you, madam?
Take the same way back
and you'II find it.
Don't cry.
She'II never find her money!
Of course she will! Nobody looks
at the ground these days
even if it's covered with gold!
Go ahead, sweetie.
Wipe your tears now.
Take the same road
and you might find it.
- Hello, Savage, how're you?
- Get lost!
What is it, honey?
Why're you crying?
I wanted to buy a goldfish,
but I lost my money.
- That's OK. I'll buy one for you.
- No.
Where did you lose it?
Which road did you go down?
Go back the same way and you'll
find it. Stop crying now. Go on.
You're still here?
Didn't you find your money?
No, I didn't.
You're right, it's hard.
Where do you live?
- Over there.
- I'll come with you.
Think hard.
Do you remember where you lost it?
Did you pass by this place?
Over there,
next to the snake charmers.
Where is your bowl?
Why aren't you carrying it?
- I left it in the shop.
- But why?
I won't take it back
till I get my goldfish!
That's where I stopped.
Here! Why did you come here?
You shouldn't have.
This is no place for you!
Have you seen
a single girl like yourself
or a woman like me here?
Haven't your parents ever told you
not to come here?
Every time we went past this place,
I'd ask my parents
to let me watch a bit,
but they never wanted to.
Once, before I started school,
I saw a man watching
with his daughter on his shoulders,
so I asked my father
to lift me up as well,
but he said
this was no place for girls.
He pulled me away
and made me follow him.
Today, as I went past,
I suddenly saw
that my mother was walking
ahead of me, so I stopped to see.
Here we go again!
I told you, this is no place for you.
I wanted to see
what was not good for me...
what they never let me see.
Have you understood now
why it's not good for you?
Yes.
So you won't come back here
any more?
No, but there are snake charmers
here all the time, aren't there?
You've forgotten your promise!
When did you last see your money?
When I gave it to the Dervish.
You gave your money to him?
Are you sure
he gave it back to you?
Yes, but it wasn't him.
The other man, the one
with the white hair gave it to me.
Where do you last remember
seeing it?
At the cake shop.
The one at the corner
of the big avenue.
I stopped and looked in the window.
I looked at the cream puffs
and at my bowl, before going away.
This is the cake shop.
Where were you standing?
Come, I'II show you.
Over here.
But there is no money here.
I'm sure it was here.
Come, let's go closer and look.
And what if I don't find it?
I'll tell your mother
that it wasn't your fault.
Whose fault is it then,
if not mine?
It is yours actually!
But I'Iljust tell her that
to calm her down.
My money!
You've worn me out, little girl.
Let me sit down for a minute.
- We'll go to Mr. Bakhtiari's.
- What about my money?
But you just found it!
We'll go to the shop owner
before he goes home
for the New Year's celebrations.
We'll ask him to give
your money back to you.
And you'II take it
and buy your goldfish.
This is all that matters.
Come on, let's go.
My regards to your father.
- Hello, Mr. Bakhtiari.
- Hello, madam.
Nice to see you again.
How are you doing?
May I ask you a favour?
This little girl's money
has fallen in the cellar.
Could you give it back to her?
It's fallen in the cellar next door.
OK.
Why are you still crying?
You found your money!
You can go and buy your fish.
I have to go now.
Goodbye and Happy New Year.
Same to you. Goodbye.
- Finished that shirt?
- There's still one sleeve left.
Do this one first.
The client'll be here any minute.
He'II make a fuss again!
Take this one as well
and finish it after the other one.
Hurry up.
What's wrong?
The collar's too big?
You wanted it this way.
You even brought me a pattern.
I made it like the pattern.
Look, this is another client's order.
I've written it all down here.
I've done exactly what he asked for.
It's true that the collar is too big.
And I actually never make
shirts like this.
But it's not my fault.
You chose the pattern.
Don't get angry.
I just asked you to change it.
Look, I have a small face.
Even on the shirt I'm wearing now,
the collar is small, you see?
I can't change the collar.
You have to take it as it is.
Don't waste my time.
It's New Year's Day
and I still have other clients.
Why are you being such a pain?
You're being stubborn!
I'm not being stubborn.
I've done my job. It's up to you
to wear the shirt or not!
What's the matter, little girl?
My money's fallen by the shop
with the metal shutter.
You mean next door?
I wanted to go buy a goldfish.
My mother gave me
the money for the fish.
If you don't want to change it now,
promise you'll do it next week.
My dear friend, you don't seem
to understand that it's not possible.
I'm not responsible for your neck
nor your face nor your head.
Stop telling me your head
is too big or too small.
Why don't you have it repaired?
It's not my job.
I don't repair heads!
I'm not responsible for that.
I just do my job.
Take it.
The rest is not my business.
It's not my fault.
The problem is in your own body.
It won't take you
more than half an hour.
It's not like chopping a piece of
wood. I'd have to change the collar.
What've I done to deserve this?
- How much is the fish?
- 1500 tomans.
I found my money, sir.
Here you are again.
I'd told you that you'd find it.
It was not worth
worrying and crying.
Where is it now?
I don't have it on me.
It's fallen into a shop's cellar.
I wanted to get it,
but the shop owner
was arguing with a man.
I just came to see
if my fish was still here.
I'm going back
to take my money out.
But you won't sell my fish now,
will you?
Don't worry, little missy,
but promise to come and buy it.
Which one do you want?
That one.
The one which is as white as a bride.
It's really pretty and chubby.
I want that one.
You'll have the one that's as pretty
as you are, but it costs 200.
My mother told me
to spend only 100.
OK, it doesn't matter.
You can take it
when you get your money back.
I'II give you the other 100 myself.
- OK?
- No. I won't take it now.
Why? You can take it now.
No, I won't.
Just promise not to sell it.
I promise, little missy.
I'll keep an eye on it
till you come back.
Where is your goldfish bowl?
Give it to me.
I put it here
while you were talking to that lady.
- I didn't see any bowl.
- Of course you did!
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes.
Mohammed!
This little girl tells me
she left her bowl in the shop.
Fill one of the bowls with water.
Here it is.
- Where're you going?
- For water.
Come back quickly.
Here's your little fish.
All pretty and round.
But this one is all skinny!
I wanted a chubby one.
You're looking at it from above.
It looks skinny that way. Watch now!
See how big it is!
You have to look at it this way.
It's round and pretty,
a real beauty. Take it!
I'll go get my money first.
You can pay me later, I don't mind.
No, I'll be right back.
Where were you all this time?
What's happened to your face?
None of your business!
Where's your bowl and the money?
I lost the money.
You lost it?
No, not really.
First I lost it,
but then I found it.
Where is it now?
You idiot!
We'II never be able to get it out.
What're we going to do then?
We'll try to get it out.
But how?
Whose shop is it?
The owner is the man
next to the tree.
Which one?
The one who's leaning against it.
He's the one who started arguing.
I won't take this sort of a thing
from a youth!
He kept telling me
that his head was too small,
that his neck was too long,
that the collar didn't fit him.
It's not my problem.
Don't get angry again!
Drink some water.
- Here, take a smoke.
- He's young enough to be your son.
I might have done it
if he hadn't started...
You should've given him a shirt
for New Year.
It's not my fault
if his head is too small!
He could have it repaired elsewhere!
I made him the shirt he asked for.
Two years ago, he did
exactly the same thing to me.
He was in the army last year.
He should've stayed there!
He doesn't have a penny in his pocket,
but keeps giving orders.
Do the shirt this way,
do it that way!
It's good to remember who you are,
where you come from
and what you're worth!
So what shouldn't have happened
has happened!
I couldn't control myself.
But I don't feel good about it.
Sir, my money.
Still here?
Why haven't you gone home?
We should be going, Mr. Bakhtiari.
Sorry about the trouble. Goodbye.
Where're you going?
Stay where you are.
- Have you finished the blue shirt?
- Yes.
Where is he now?
Filing a complaint against you.
- Is the shop next door yours?
- No, some one else's.
Can I leave now?
Are you done with your work?
Good.
- Have you done everything?
- Yes.
- Where're you going?
- My home town.
Don't forget a present for me.
Could I have my money back please?
Here's a box of pastry and 2 shirts.
Happy New Year to you.
Don't forget.
I'll see you in a week's time.
I'd like to go back home
- if you allow me -
till the thirteenth.
All right, but no longer.
We have a lot of work.
I'II be back on time. Goodbye.
What do you want?
My money.
It's not my shop
and the owner has gone on a trip.
Come back after New Year
and you'll get your money.
- It's right next door.
- Where the girl pointed to?
- She's my sister.
- What can I do about it?
- Can't you take the money out?
- I'm not the owner.
Is Hossein in Tehran?
Impossible. You know him!
He's out of town
whenever he can.
He goes along with his wife's whims!
He's certainly gone now.
But don't worry about your money.
It's in a safe place.
Go home now
and come back next week
and you'll get your money.
Try to understand.
- Forget about it.
- What must I do?
- What more do you want?
- My money.
I don't have the keys to the shop.
Come back next week.
Mr. Bakhtiari...
let me come back here
with your client.
- He must've realized his mistake.
- OK, if you really insist.
- Thanks for your concern.
- I'll see you later then.
- What can we do?
- I don't know.
How should I know!
The shop is closed
and the owner is on a trip.
I'll help you next week.
Go now.
There is exactly 42 minutes
and 20 seconds left till the New Year.
The sea is rough, brother,
the sea is rough...
How can I get it?
What do you want, my boy?
- My money's stuck there.
- I can't do anything for you.
- Can I borrow this from you?
- What?
The rod you use
for the metal shutter.
Why?
It's only for a minute.
OK, but hurry up. I have to leave.
Try it from the side of the grid.
What're you up to?
I don't know!
What do you mean?
You'll never manage this way!
Give that to me.
I'll try to get it out.
It's impossible.
This is good for the shutter,
but not for this.
If only we could turn the hook
the other way...
Can you do it?
Impossible. The hook is welded.
It's not made for this.
It's just to pull the shutter down.
Go home and come back
in a week's time.
The owner will be back by then
and you'll get your money.
Is the anniversary
of his death close?
Yes.
But I can't leave right now.
I'll go the day after tomorrow.
Won't it be too late?
No, it'll be the right time.
Come on, kids.
Don't stay here.
You're going to draw attention.
I'll take care of it
after the holidays.
I'll find the owner.
The money's safe.
Nobody can take it.
Go home now
or else your parents will get worried.
We should've asked him
for the address.
Whose address?
I mean, the owner's address.
Wait here, I'll be back.
What happened?
It was a relative of his.
He might still be here.
Wait.
I want to ask you something.
Does Mum know about this?
Don't talk to me now
or I'll forget the address.
I'll be right back.
I don't see any money in there!
It's a 500 note!
Is that why you're so worried?
Here, take some sunflower seeds.
I'll see if I can help you.
Please take some.
You don't want any?
I also have some pastries
if you don't like those.
Shall I open the box?
It looks like
you don't want that either!
What're you worrying about?
I won't eat you or your money!
So what're you scared of?
I saw you were staring down there
and I thought I might help you!
You shouldn't be scared of me.
I'm a nice guy!
If you don't answer
I won't talk to you any more.
But... I know
where the shop owner lives.
He lives in that street
where your brother went.
But your brother's not going
to find him. Know why?
Because he's not home.
He's invited to my sister-in-law's!
Your sister-in-law's?
He might be there already
or still on his way.
It's hard to say, because...
her house is 700
or 800 kilometers away from here.
You know...
my little sister's your age.
You're about 5, aren't you?
Not at all. I'm 7.
My sister is 5 years old, like you.
She doesn't go to school yet.
Wrong again.
I'm 7 and I go to school.
I'm in first grade
and also first in my class.
I get A's all the time.
Now what do you say to that?
My other sister's in third grade.
She's also very good at school.
But you look more like the one
who's 5 who doesn't go to school yet.
What?
What do you mean?
My 2 sisters...
One's a bit older than you
and the other one is a bit younger.
I'm dying to see them.
If you're dying to see them,
why don't you then?
They live far away.
- Where?
- In Neyshabour.
You're from Neyshabour? Like
my Dad's friend, Mr. Neyshabouri.
But he doesn't talk like you.
He must've lived here
a long time then
to have lost his accent.
If I stayed here long enough,
I could also speak
without an accent.
How long have you been in Tehran?
Around a year.
When are you leaving?
When I'm done in the army
or when I get leave.
Don't soldiers get a few days off
for New Year? The schools are closed!
Even my Dad doesn't go to work.
Everybody is off for New Year.
Nobody works.
We get a few days off too,
but I decided not to go away.
- I'll stay here.
- You lied about seeing your sisters.
No, I didn't. Little missy...
you're sulking again.
I didn't lie to you.
I really want to see them.
You want to go back home
to see them?
I wanted to!
When someone really wants to see his
family, it means he wants to go home.
You're right.
You're on leave?
That means that you could
leave your... school.
No, I mean your...
My work place is called a barracks.
Why don't you leave
the barracks then?
Tell me, how many days' leave
do you have?
Our leave is also a week long,
like your Dad's.
By the way,
what's your father's job?
I don't know.
You don't know
or you don't want to tell me?
Maybe I don't want to tell you.
You needn't if you don't want to.
But I'll answer all your questions.
Why don't you go home to see your
sisters if you're dying to see them?
Especially since you're on leave!
Why don't you go?
- You want to know why?
- Yes.
Will you also tell me
your father's job?
My father has 2 jobs. I'll tell you
one but not the other.
My mother has told me
not to talk about his other job.
His first job
is at the water company.
He goes to every house
on his scooter
and he reads the meter.
You know, the paper you get
to see how much you have to pay
for the water.
But I won't tell you his other job.
I also have 2 reasons for not going.
I'll tell you the first one
but not the second... like you.
The first reason is, I don't have
enough money for the bus fare.
Plus, I have to buy presents
for my 2 sisters
and for my parents. I'd like to take
some presents with me.
That's why I can't go.
I'll try to work a bit
after my military service...
before going back home.
How much is the bus fare?
There's a special price
for soldiers.
Around 300 tomans.
What would you have bought
for your sisters?
I don't know.
Have you got any ideas?
You could get them
some chewing gum
or some chocolate maybe.
No, not chocolate.
Wait, I have a better idea...
Get them some of this.
Girls love it.
It costs 7 tomans a piece.
It'll cost 14 tomans for 2.
Buy this for them.
Can you go back with 400 tomans?
Yes, I could with 400.
Are you offering me your money?
No, that's my mother's money.
She needs it for New Year.
Oh, New Year!
I'd totally forgotten about that.
Then I have to bring them
some New Year's gifts as well.
Now that you've given me
some ideas for the presents,
take some of this sweetmeat.
And I'll try to take your money out.
Why won't you take any?
Were you told
not to take things from strangers?
Yes.
- And also not to talk to them.
- Yes.
That's why you wouldn't talk
to me at first.
Yes.
It's true I don't know you,
but I'm not a stranger!
How could you not know me
and not be a stranger?
Well, I'm doing my military service
here, but I don't know anyone
and nobody knows me either. I'm
a stranger, but I don't feel like one.
What does that mean?
When I first saw you,
I got the feeling we knew each other.
So I came closer to talk to you.
I felt like your brother.
All right, I'm not a stranger to you,
but you don't have my brother's age!
So you're a stranger to me.
I was told not to accept things from
strangers and not to talk to them.
Shall I tell my sisters
to do the same?
Haven't you told them that before?
No, because we live in a small village
where people know each other.
There are no strangers back home.
But here, people don't know
one another.
They don't interact,
so they feel like strangers.
Come here.
- What were you blabbering about?
- We were talking about his sisters.
Haven't you been told
not to talk to strangers?
But he's not a stranger.
What?
He has a sister my age...
A little bit younger
or a bit older...
It's not the end of the world!
Just wait till we get home
and you'll see.
Listen...
Your sister didn't talk to me.
Of course I did!
I'll show you when we get home!
Don't scold her.
Here, take some of these.
Well, I have to go back
to the barracks now.
Don't be so sad, little girl.
Goodbye.
They look great.
What do?
Your shoes.
But they're not new.
I know. But the polish is!
- Did you find his house?
- Yes I did.
- Was he home?
- Yes, but he was taking a shower.
What shall we do
if he doesn't come?
No idea.
What do we do now?
I don't know.
I left him a message
to come here after his shower.
What if he were like Dad?
Angry before the shower
and sleepy afterwards!
He wouldn't show up.
What will we do then?
I don't know.
If that shop was still open,
I would've taken the hook...
and I would have twisted it
to take the money out.
How?
I would've put
something sticky on the end.
- Thief!
- Thief, yourself.
- You stole my balloons.
- I didn't!
I'll show you!
Let my brother go.
Leave him alone.
I don't want the money any more.
Stop it!
Let him go.
- It was to get our money out.
- Which money?
- The goldfish money.
- Look. Don't you have eyes?
Get up, little brother.
I don't see any money.
Put your face down and if
you're not blind, you'll see it.
Shade your eyes with your hands.
Get away.
Let me do it.
There's no point.
If we had something sticky,
it'd work.
Like what?
Like glue or chewing gum.
Have you got any chewing gum?
Where would I get it from?
Am I a chewing gum seller!
What a cheek!
- Do you have some change?
- I don't have a penny.
Look in your pocket.
- What for?
- Just do as I say.
But I never keep money
in this pocket!
Stop being a pain.
Here, I always have
one of these in my pocket.
Wait here.
I'll go get some chewing gum.
I'm late. I have to sell my balloons.
You can sell them here.
- How much is this chewing gum?
- Which?
5 tomans.
Here's 10. Give me 5 back.
- Where's the Afghan boy?
- Gone.
Why did you let him go?
He left on his own.
But I didn't talk to him.
Which way did he go?
That way.
- Did you buy any?
- No.
Let's try with your fruit-roll.
But we don't have a stick.
You haven't eaten it, have you?
I bet you have.
Here, take it.
I don't want it any more.
Look, it's him!
Where were you?
Give me your stick.
Kids, I've bought chewing gum.
Let's play a game.
Stop!
- I won.
- I did!
No, I won the game.
- Do you have it? Careful!
- Let me try.
It's my turn now.
- If you can't get it, it's my turn.
- OK.
- Slowly.
- Careful! Oh, it fell again.
My turn.
Once more. Then, you try.
- You don't do it right.
- Let me try.
What's up?
What's going on here?
Our money has fallen down here.
- Which money?
- My sister's money.
Is that why you made me
come here on New Year's Eve?
Is this your shop?
Yes and what can I do for you?
Is it possible to get our money out?
Your telephone
kept ringing non-stop.
You should've answered
to see if it was
what's-his-name.
- Give it to me.
- Here, take it.
Here's your stick.
Goodbye, sir.
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Why did you make me come
if you could do it yourselves?
The sea is rough, brother,
the sea is rough...
Is the sea still rough, my friend?
Time to go home now.
Do you have matches?
Why should I have matches?
I'm not a matchseller!
Do you have a match?
You didn't shut it.
I would've told you,
had I not shut it.
Did you find your money, little girl?
Yes, we did.
And you bought your fish. See?
No point crying. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year to you too.
Are you coming?
What're you waiting for?
Year 1374 of the solar calendar
has just begun...