Coming up...
The Double of...
at the One O'clock Show
Wait here please
-Can I help you?
-No.
Please wait here a minute,
someone's coming right away.
Gentlemen, we have five minutes
so please, raise you hands.
Carlos Carvajal, Carlos Carvajal...
José Rivas...
-Francisco Palma...
-Here.
Jaime Pena...
Girls, this way please...
Girls, this way please.
Go inside, behind th curtain,
on the right side please.
Hugo Muñoz, Hugo Muñoz...
Sir...what about you?
Tony Manero.
Wait a second please.
Right, I'm coming right away.
There is a guy here for next week's contest.
Tony Manero.
Don't worry I'll talk to him.
Hi, excuse me...
How cool!
Your turn is next week.
I was told it was today.
No, its next week.
Oh, its not today?
No, you didn't understand,
we tell people
to come to register a week
in advance...Wait a second please.
-What's wrong with Chuck Norris?
-There's three missing.
No, bring them in, we give them
the instructions, and then go in, OK?
A button has come off.
What?
Under the zipper there are two buttons.
It's well known.
-Enrique!
-Hi.
Attention please! My name is
Juana, I'm the producer of this contest.
And I'm going to give you a couple of tips.
Come in, silence please.
A couple of tips before we
get in the studio OK?
We are going insode through this
part of the stage, very quietly.
Dirty jokes are not allowed,
no government talk,
And no bad words.
Three basic premises.
Whats your name?
Raul Peralta Paredes.
Date of birth?
Your age, sir?
52.
Address?
What for?
Are you from Santiago?
Santiago it is.
Occupation?
This.
This what?
Show business.
-Hello.
It started a half an hour ago...
Thank you, sir.
Fucking boys!
They smashed my kidneys!
Thank you, sir.
I live not so far away.
These people... you know...
come from a bad race.
Thank God there are decent people like you.
Come in sir...
Put the bags over there, please.
This is for you.
The expitation date is last year
but it tastes good.
We like it very much.
It's a color TV.
I've got it because I'm an
Air Force officer's widow.
...the president is about to sign a decree that
declares the Cueca as the national dance...
Look how she pays attention to you.
Did you know that General Pinochet
has blue eyes?
No, I didn't know.
Strange, ah? With so many Mapuches around.
...the runners get to Alameda with a 150 meter
lead over the others...
-Attention there...
-Yes...
To the side...
Up...
To the other side...
Look!
Pauli...
Look at me...
Where were you?
I was waiting for you.
I'm fresh, I very clean.
Polish the boys Raul!
-You're late.
-What?
From the beginning...
Side...
Other side...
Free style...
Leave me alone!
Again...
What happened?
Goyo... you believe
you're the greatest artist...
...No...but he doesn't like this.
He prefers other things,
Different things,
-More profound things like folklore...
-Thats right...
Yes, sure...
How do you call it? "Roots?"
Right Goyo?
Sorry...
right, comrade Goyo?
Whats the problem?
I like both.
We are all together in this!
"All together..."
Shut up you communist!
Here we've come to work.
This is our job.
You have to start doing the show properly,
Professionally.
So the audience comes.
You should go to the movies,
to see Tony.
He knows.
I would like to see Raul in the new suit.
Hasn't he put it on yet?
It would be nice.
Cool!
Put it on, put it on...
I'll wear it on Saturday.
Ouch, what a fall!
Are you OK? These planks are all rotten.
You have to stand up over
there Cony and that's it.
What are you doing Raul?
Stop it!
-You're screwing up my bar!
-But its all rotten!
You are killing my business!
-Stop it, you asshole!
-Let me alone!
We can hardly pay the bills
and you are ruining the floor!
-Stop it!
-Shut up mother fucker!
Its all rotten!
-Give me the jacket!
-Son of a bitch.
You are the bitch.
Fucking floor...
Touch it, touch it.
This is the cathedral-type glass.
And this is the smoked one.
-Besides we have delivery service.
-Really?
Yes, we use that American Ford,
the light blue one.
Are you two together?
Too fat...
What?
It's to dance on. It has to be firm.
You need a high density glass...
Touch it.
How big is the floor?
It would be $74,285.
How much?
$74, 085,
It's an imported product.
I can offer you a better price.
$60,000.
But no delivery.
OK. We might come back later
with the money.
Nice.
...We're back here, at the One O'Clock Show
to share lunch together...
Friends
soon we're going to have
the Chuck Norris final.
"The Double of...Chuck Norris..."
And now I will invite all the disco dancers
Attention to the admirers of
that American dancer...
But what happened?
-Don't take it away.
-Oh, he's going to watch it alone.
It doesn't look good.
It must be the antenna.
What, the floor?
Come over here.
And why do you want that?
To light up from below.
This is what you need.
Whats that?
High densities.
I must have enough for
you to make your floor,
but the TV is not enough.
But...its a color TV.
Yes, but this glass is very expensive.
I'll give you 20 for the TV.
Things cost what they cost
not what you want them to cost.
And I set the price, not you.
Hey kid, watch out!
What are you up to?
I don't like these strange gatherings.
Easy Ms. Wilma, we are moving the
pieces of the new floor.
-What is this for?
-For an effect.
Where is the hair dye?
-Huh?
-The Percolett.
Yes wait. do you want some help?
What for?
The Percolett?
-The Percolett?
-Yes the Percolett.
-It must be in the bedroom.
-Where?
...in the bathroom...
Is it in the bedroom or the bathroom?
I'm not sure. I think I saw it in the bedroom.
Where?
Over there.
In the bedroom?
No, its in the bathroom.
Hey, please come over here...
You look OK.
Probably its in the bathroom.
These people don't think about the future.
What future?
You're future, my future,
their future.
They don't think.
But i know we'll make it
with our dance couple.
But, we have to get out of here.
Why?
Just because.
After all Pauli is a grown up now.
She's educated.
However, we have to do it quickly.
-Why?
-Because time is going by,
And the Tony Manero of the movies
is never going to grow old.
But you are getting old.
You are lifeless.
You can't even get a hardon.
It gets swollen, but not hard.
Your glass floor is the only thing
that can turn you on.
You are a fool.
That other one is a Yankee,
You aren't.
You belong here
like the rest of us.
We all live in the same neighborhood.
Not anymore,
What about me?
Tomorrow...
I get my red dress,
like the one in the film.
It's white.
It's red, you can see it in the poster.
It isn't white.
Go see the movie again.
And you?
Would you like to go with me?
You are old enough,
go by yourself.
You know what?
You and I are the same thing.
My clothes are ready.
The waist is a little too tight.
But I'm going to fix it.
That's very nice...
It's the same. White suit,
black shirt,
the trousers and the button.
What is it with you?
Did you take your suit for a walk?
What do you mean by "the button?"
There's two buttons.
Its one button.
Two buttons.
One.
I'm telling you there's two buttons.
One is ablove the zipper,
next to the brooch. One.
Beautiful.
Have you tried it on?
There's one button missing,
but it looks the same.
Put it on to see how it looks on you.
You can try it on with the music and everything.
You have to pay for it to the last penny.
Stay there or I'll shoot!
Stay there!
Freeze mother fucker!
Freeze!
Give me that!
What does he have there?
What do you think?
I'm just going home!
You don't have to ask anything!
Where did you get it?
I'm just going home.
What's your name?
-I'm just going home.
-I asked for your name.
José, José...
José is my name.
OK well,
Where do you live?
Here on the other side,
just on the other side.
OK, relax, you're coming with us.
It's part of the procedure.
Where are you living?
Answer me!
Who gave you this?
Shit!
No, no.
-Who is you contact?
-Gregorio.
-What's the skinny guys name?
-Goyo! Goyo!
GET OUT PINOCHET!
Are you going to rehearse?
It's too strange doing the whole rehearsal
without you, because we follow you.
There is no body reference.
But it is entirely possible.
How would it be
possible if he is not in front?
-It's possible.
-It's too difficult.
You know, this part was created by Goyo,
if you want we can take it out.
It would be better if it was just you and me.
What did you say?
-Speak up!
-Nothing...
We should do Raul's choreography.
I mean...Im not sure about
the new steps you created.
You and Raul alone...
Is that what you want?
-Yes, I do.
-what about me, mom?
You and Raul alone...
What about us?
We simply look at you?
Does he speak English?
Look, I've been thinking,
that Tomas, you and me
could leave this place.
Where?
Far away from here.
Without the other two whores.
Because I think you
can see the difference
between me and them.
Don't make that face.
I really love you.
Do you think when you become old
fashioned they will continue to follow you?
No way.
This is not fashion.
Tomas, how many times did i tell you
not to play here with the ball?
Stop it.
Hey, that's the mirror we need
to get ready for the show.
OK, go and help your mother.
On Saturday, I want to see you on
your fucking stage with glass shit.
Pauli...
Oh my God,
Where have you been?
Downtown.
But...how...
I walked here, there weren't any buses.
Goyo is helping people cross the streets.
Everything is flooded.
And the military is doing nothing.
What do you mean
they are doing nothing?
Show some respect.
Now the country is tidy.
Things are working...I'll go
for a bigger towel.
What happened to you?
I came here walking and it is raining.
What are you doing?
Wilma went for a towel.
What are you doing
here naked, you whore!
-But mom...
-Put some clothes on!
Come on, put it on...
Hurry up!
-It looks good on me.
-Go inside!
Go inside!
Fever?
It's not showing.
There's another with the
same gentleman.
No problem, come on in.
Thank you.
Can I use the radio a bit?
Yes.
You know what?
We put together
something to show you.
If you like it you can
add it to the show.
But that's not in the movie.
We would like to cooperate
with the choreography.
What's that?
This is mine.
Hey, is the show with Chilean music?
No, its international.
Want some?
Move it you little shits!
Look, Raul...
This is my capital. The money
you gave me is your capital.
Well...you know, its not easy.
Prices went up, OK? now you are going
to take less glass bricks for the same money.
You can take...
18, and you take them yourself.
Should I open the gate?
You're going to need a lot more bricks.
-Is Goyo outside?
-Yes.
-Did you bring...the potatoes...
-Shut up.
Help us.
Did you get the flyers?
Yeah, I got them!
Stay calm! Stay calm!
Wilma is inside...
I saw her...
And are you still at it?
What do you have over there?
-Potatoes.
-I told you to bring onions.
I brought potatoes anyway.
What are you up to?
Helping.
I know exactly what you've got yourself
involved in.
I'm not like Wilma.
How many times did I tell you
not to get into that shit?
How many?
Don't get the wrong idea , mom.
Stop putting ideas into
my daughter's head.
She's a grownup.
She's where she has to be.
Yeah, sure.
What's going on?
Nothing...
Hey, do you have a few bones?
Look...
-I have a Seiko myself.
-Yes, but this is a new one.
Why are you dressed like that?
Play the B side.
It says 1 and 2.
2 is B.
And the white suit?
None of your business.
Weren't you supposed
to wear it tonight?
It was missing a button.
Hurry up everybody,
we're almost ready.
We'll go up on stage and
we'll dance like we've never danced before.
Together, like a family, united.
Today life is giving us a chance.
A chance to...
Shut up Goyo!
You sound like a preacher.
Here's our national Tony Manero
and his dance group.
It's crowded!
It's full of people!
There wasn't enough
fish for everybody.
And there wont be enough wine
for those two.
Stop drinkning and start cleaning up!
You drank it all!
Leave me alone.
Sir, there's half an hour until curfew,
so we are done.
Don't curfew me.
Time to go home.
The army is acting wild,
so you better get home.
Don't you want to eat something?
No, only Fanta.
What are you looking at?
A bird that shits in the nest
is a bad bird.
Raul...
Don't get dizzy sweetheart.
Come with me.
It's alright.
Did you have a good sleep?
You're going to end up shitting a bastard.
Come with me.
Did you have fun last night?
What made you decide
to have a bath?
Goyo tell us!
-What?
-Ask Goyo to tell us...
What?
Nothing. My business.
Tell us.
Come on. Tell everyone.
What's the secret?
I'm going to the TV station.
To the TV station?
Yes, to the TV station.
He's going to be on the One O'Clock Show.
They are looking for the Chilean Tony Manero.
I have the white suit and everything.
Just like Raul's?
-But mine.
-Can you imagine?
When are you going?
-Today.
-Today?
Raul should go too.
We'll have a better chance to win.
You're right. You're the winner.
He's too young to win.
Plus, he's too dark.
And he has brown eyes.
You are clumsy on your birthday.
No cake for you!
It was an accident...
Pay attention!
Calling Paulina Garces Garces?
Miss Paulina Garces Garces!
That's me. What do you need me for?
OK.
Sit down.
Come together everyone.
We need to discuss something important.
OK, everybody out.
You...get over here.
We have to talk.
Cony.
Here, sit next to me.
Did you hear me motherfuckers?
Raul! You're an asshole!
Let's get out of here!
Raul!
Where is he?
No idea.
What do you mean?
Where's Raul?
Sit down!
What's the matter?
What do you mean what's the matter?
I told you to sit down jerk!
Hey Cony.
Who is this guy?
Why don't you ask me?
Shut up punk! Stay cool.
Who's Raul?
Who else lives here?
No, no. Sometimes he comes.
Marcelo, go upstairs.
What's the matter?
We were told
strange things happen in this place.
People talk.
I haven't done anything wrong.
-Oh really?
-Really.
Nothing wrong...
Ask your mom.
This is your daughter, right?
You can't change your mind now.
Is this your daughter or not?
Yes.
Goyo, say something.
Tell him.
You said it was safe.
Say something.
What's your name?
Gregorio Salinas.
And your full name?
Acuna.
And your nickname?
Goyo.
OK.
We're going to have a talk.
There's a procedure...
There's nobody upstairs.
This is Goyo.
Come on! Shit!
Let's get this over with now!
Come here!
Take it easy Pauli!
Take it easy!
Talk damn it!
Who is the guy from the print shop?
What print shop? What print shop?
Talk damn it!
Get on the floor!
Gentlemen, please wait in line here.
Please.
We are about to go on the air
with you.
Silence please, behind the light.
Everybody inside.
Excuse me!
How's everybody doing?
Hello!
Very good.
A little money is better than none.
Now that you are here, I want to say something;
Last year,
we almost went to war against Argentina,
but now we are friends again.
To express our wish for peace
we've hired an Argentinian model, Vanessa!
Sir, come with me please.
As you said earlier, we shouldn't be fighting
over a piece of land.
-It's not worth it.
Applause for Vanessa.
Today we considered for our female audience...
You probably all saw "Saturday Night Fever,"
Right?
Starring that great dancer,
John Travolta.
Travolta plays Tony Manero.
We're searching now for the Chilean Tony Manero,
follow me, little camera.
Let's invite to the stage our first
contestant.
He says: "I'm Tony Manero!"
I'm unemployed right now.
If you win today, you can participate
in the final contest and get $70,000!
-Would that work?
-Oh yeah!
Ladies and gentlemen
Enrique says: "I'm Tony Manero!"
Let's invite to the stage
contesetant number 5!
How are you doing?
What's your name?
Raul Peralta Paredes O.
Paredes like in that Tango.
Do you like Tango?
Yes.
What do you do for a living?
This.
You mean dancing?
Great! Withi enthusiasm
and energy!
He says: "I'm Tony Manero!"
You are the jury, dear audience.
Your applause will decide.
Applause for number 1, Sergio!
For number 2, Sebastian!
For number 3, Enrique!
Fro number 4, Jaun!
For number 5, Raul!
For number 6!
It's not clear enough.
Numbers 3 and 5 come with me.
We have to repeat the applause
becasue I'm not sure who is the winner.
Applause for number 3!
Applause for number 5!
And the winner is...
number 3, Enrique!
Did you bring someone
with you?
With my wife.
Come on down!
We have a beautiful present
here for you.
Its a blender!
The contestants will receive Poncho Lindo, Tizona
guitars and a package of Salsital.
I want to invite everyone to our next contest:
the Chilean Julio Iglesias.
You can come this week
to register yourself.